Alexandra Kuksa | Front-end Developer

LinkedIn

Current location: St. Petersburg, Russia

Portfolio Telegram

<u>kooksa.codes</u> <u>alexkooksa</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/alexkooksa</u>

E-mail

alex.kooksa@gmail.com



Summary

I have over 7 years of experience in web development, participating in more than 100 projects of varying scales as both a front-end developer and designer. Visual aspect is important for me. I enjoy creating and bringing to life thoughtful and logical designs, and paying attention to details. When developing, I prioritize finding the most rational solutions and writing code that is scalable and easy to maintain. I highly value well-established processes and genuine feedback.

Hard skills

 $\textbf{Languages and tools:} \ \mathsf{HTML, CSS} \ / \ \mathsf{SASS, JavaScript, Smarty,}$

Eleventy, Nunjucks, Git

Libs: JQuery + plugins (Swiper, Fancybox etc.), AOS, GSAP

Design: interface prototyping, typography,

UI/UX optimization

Software: Figma, Adobe XD, Photoshop, Illustrator **Currently mastering**: modern Vanilla JavaScript, React

Soft skills

- · I am organized and always prioritize tasks
- · I admit mistakes and learn from feedback
- I enjoy teamwork and finding the best solution together
- I am also responsible and am able to make decisions on my own
- When making a decision, I am weighing different options and am able to communicate my reasoning clearly
- Empathy is my second name (while positive attitude is the third one)

Languages

- · Russian (native)
- · Limited Working English

Education

Bachelor's degree, Information Technology

Sep 2008 - Jun 2013

Peter the Great St.Petersburg Polytechnic University

Student exchange program, Connected Environments

Feb 2012 - Jun 2012

L'École de design Nantes Atlantique

Experience

Web Developer

Sep 2022 - Present • Self-employed / Remote

- · websites and apps development
- · coding, CMS development
- · UI/UX design

Middle Front-end Developer

Oct 2017 - Sep 2022 • Evernet / On-site

Since 2022 I've been working mainly on projects for Bright Rich.

Responsibilities:

- extended scope of responsibility within the company;
- participation in all stages of project development: design, creation of templates and layout for CMS, content management, customization of modules for output of client content in the admin panel, maintenance and implementation of new features after launch;
- making simple changes on back-end (PHP);
- collaborating with client's team (designers, marketing specialists);
- · making usability audits.

Junior Front-end Developer + UI/UX Designer

Oct 2016 - Sep 2017 • Evernet / On-site

- extended scope of responsibility within the company;
- development of the responsive layouts based on my own and client's designs;
- · teamwork with a full-stack developer;
- projects maintenance: design and coding of new components, optimization of existing components, bug fixing.

Web Designer

Feb 2016 - Sep 2016 • Evernet / On-site

- creating design layouts for new websites
- redesign of existing client websites
- maintenance of completed projects (working with content, making edits)

+ 2 years in printing design